<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicholas James Rich</title>
    <description>Article and Short Fiction Writer, Editor, and Freelance Translator</description>
    <link>/jekyll-uno//</link>
    <atom:link href="/jekyll-uno//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 13:04:41 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 13:04:41 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching at a Junior High School in Japan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Deciding to become a teacher in Japan offers a lot of exciting opportunities to enjoy unique experiences and insight into an amazing culture. But it’s important to know which work environment is best for you, so we’re here to give you the basics about teaching at the junior high school (JHS) level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Japanese Junior High School?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post-elementary school education in Japan is a little different from its Western counterpart, which can be confusing at first. At a JHS in the United States, for example, you’ll typically find students between the ages of 11 to 13 in grades six, seven, and eight, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a junior high school in Japan, also called a chu-gakko (literally, middle school), students are usually between the ages of 13 to 15, and it covers the seventh, eighth and ninth years of a student’s education. However, naming conventions for school years in Japan are a bit different, as they refer to the time spent at a particular type of school, not the overall time in the education system. At a JHS in Japan, the grade levels are first year (ichi-nen-sei), second year (ni-nen-sei) and third year (san-nen-sei), respectively. Class sizes vary depending on the area, but are typically between 28 to 40 students per class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting that junior high schools in Japan all look relatively similar, regardless of their location throughout the country. They’re rectangular, multi-floor buildings with a large school ground for sports activities, and may have various other facilities like a pool. It often feels like once you’ve seen one, you’ve seen them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Day-to-Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every student in a public junior high school will wear a school uniform that, while similar, is unique to their school. The concept of a homeroom also isn’t strange in Western education, but a homeroom at a chu-gakko is the room where assigned students will have all of their classes except gym, cooking, art, and some science lessons. Throughout the day, teachers float in and out of the rooms to teach their assigned subjects, with students staying put. Classes are typically 50 minutes long, with four in the morning, a break for lunch, and then two in the afternoon, though sometimes classes will be shortened to 45 minutes to make time for assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to after-school club activities, or bukatsu-do, often simply shortened to bukatsu. In junior high school, all students are strongly encouraged to join an after-school club to help foster friendship with schoolmates and teachers, and develop a greater sense of loyalty and belonging to the school. The variety and number of clubs depends on the size and resources of the school, but they’re often related to sports, music, art and hobbies. Regardless of the club, students are required to attend every day, and participate in events after school, on weekends and even during holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that, as a teacher, you’ll have plenty of opportunity to visit these clubs and see how they work, and what sorts of things they actually get up to. Often the teachers in charge of the clubs will invite you to check them out, and maybe even participate. Just make sure they know that you’re visiting—and not joining—as you’ll be subject to all the obligations of a normal club member if they think you’ve signed up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where You Come In&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your actual job as an English teacher at a JHS will vary depending on the type of school you’re at and the needs and expectations of the faculty. But there’s a general structure to help you know what you should expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you’ll basically never be alone in a classroom, unlike at an eikaiwa (English conversation school), or during private lessons. There will always be a Japanese teacher of English (JTE) in the room, although their role in class will depend on their personality and teaching style, as well as potential contractual restrictions depending on whether you’re directly employed by the board of education or working for an external contractor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some JTEs will take charge of a classroom, and utilize your English abilities to help iron out pronunciation issues, introduce new vocabulary, and facilitate learning activities. Other times, JTEs will take the back seat and you’ll lead the entire class, with the JTE stepping in to help demonstrate activities with you, or provide clarification to students when necessary. You shouldn’t be speaking Japanese in the class, but understanding it definitely helps you pick up on comprehension problems and identifying where students are struggling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is to firmly establish what your role in the classroom is with your JTEs so you can plan lessons accordingly, and not be caught by surprise and left open-mouthed in front of 30-plus students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A point worth noting is that classes in JHS aren’t distinguished by academic ability the way they might be in other school systems. In fact, Japanese classes are intentionally balanced so no one class is a powerhouse academically or athletically, under the belief that stronger students should learn to support the weaker ones. This means that in a class of 35, there might be some students at the top of the class who knock whatever you’re teaching them out of the park, while in that same class there will likely be students who struggle with English and feel frustrated and want to give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can make it incredibly difficult to prepare comprehensive lesson plans that cater to all levels. The key is to foster a classroom atmosphere conducive to learning, regardless of academic ability. Group activities with roles where everyone can participate and feel like they’re contributing are a great way to get around this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there’s no real way to prepare yourself for every eventuality that might come up while teaching at a junior high school in Japan, one of the biggest takeaways from my experience is simply this: be flexible. It’s a vague but essential piece of advice! Every school, every teacher, and every class is different, and so flexibility is the key to building good relationships with your coworkers and students, and making your stay at your school a positive experience for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If any of this sounds scary, forgive me—it isn’t. While the job can be difficult or frustrating at times (what job isn’t?), it can also be incredibly fun and rewarding (I’ve never had a job where 1,000 people were so excited to say “hello” to me every day!). Once you understand the teaching methods that work for you, you’ll wonder what you were worried about in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/2552/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 04:04:23 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2016/teaching-jhs-japan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2016/teaching-jhs-japan/</guid>
        
        <category>Teaching</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Six Ways to be an ALT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’ve decided you want to try living in Japan. While it’s a big decision, once you’ve decided, the easy part is over. It’s time to figure out the path that suits you best, and we’re here to help, with a brief overview of six ways to become an ALT, one of several ways you can come teach in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an ALT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ALT, or Assistant Language Teacher, is the industry term used to refer to a (usually) native English speaker who works in the public school system in Japan as an English teacher, with the only hard requirements being a college degree, as well as a formative education in an English environment (exactly what this means depends on the company you work for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the role the ALT plays at the school is determined by a lot of variables such as school level, location, etc., the job usually requires going to one or more schools a day to supplement students’ English education by providing them with an opportunity to interact with a non-Japanese English speaker and gain some insight into foreign cultures. You’ll generally have between three and six classes a day, five days a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great for anyone with an interest in working in education or working with children, and because you work in public schools, you reap the benefit of all national holidays, which affords you plenty of free time to explore the country, especially during summer vacation. As many sites will tell you, it’s a great way to get paid to experience life in Japan, whether it’s an urban environment, a rural village, or somewhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve established what an ALT is, let’s get into the nitty gritty of how to become one. We’ll take a look at six options, including a few private dispatch companies, the JET program, and direct-hire scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Interac&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interac was founded in 1972, and is the largest private provider of ALTs in the country. It operates nationally, with a network of 13 offices throughout Japan, and provides ALTs for all levels of public education. The corporate philosophy is to “promote a deeper understanding of languages, cultures, and education throughout the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most private ALT providers, Interac is considered a “dispatch” company, meaning its teachers are Interac employees dispatched to various public schools, and not employees of the schools themselves. This means that while you work in schools, you have to contact Interac about things like contracting, holidays, sick leave, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interac has recruitment for two main contract periods: one for late March/early April, to coincide with the beginning of a new school year, and one for late August, which is usually when schools come back from summer vacation. The typical starting salary is between ¥230,000 to ¥250,000 per month, although it is pro-rated in the vacation-heavy months of March, April, August and December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interac’s training usually includes a rigorous multi-day orientation to help equip you with the skills necessary for the job, and the branches have meetings for ALTs as part of their ongoing training program, though the frequency tends to vary depending on where you work. Like most private companies, Interac provides support for getting you set up with housing, opening a bank account, and other essentials for life in Japan. For more information, including how to apply, visit the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Heart English School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heart English School is another private provider of ALTs that works primarily in the Kanto region, which includes Ibaraki, Chiba, Tokyo, Saitama, Gunma and Tochigi Prefectures. Salaries for teachers tend to be lower than other dispatch companies, but the specifics depend on the number of days you’re working and whether you’re full- or part-time (for example, ¥160,000 for a four-day-a-week position).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the job description is fairly similar to other ALT companies, there are a few differences worth noting. First, Heart requests potential applicants to have a basic understanding of Japanese, or at least a strong desire to learn. While your job is teaching English, the company appreciates the bumps that can be smoothed out by communicating with Japanese school teachers in their native language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Heart works primarily in public schools, it also provides conversation classes at its own private schools, as well as corporate English lessons. Heart also provides job placement assistance for employees with N2 level Japanese or better, in the event that you decide to pursue a career in a different field. Although the website looks a bit dated, it’s frankly written and includes loads of useful information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Borderlink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borderlink came onto the scene in the year 2000 with an interest in helping students in Japan understand the world outside their country’s borders. It operates in the Kanto region, the Koshinetsu region (specifically, Niigata Prefecture), the Kansai region (Osaka, Shiga and Hyogo Prefectures), as well as the Chubu region (Aichi and Gifu Prefectures). The company provides ALTs for public schools, and the salary starts at about ¥200,000 per month, but depends on your experience and credentials. It also offers part-time work for staff during the month of August, including tutoring for speech contests or working for summer programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borderlink provides its ALTs with about a week of initial training about life in Japan, working in Japanese schools and lesson planning, as well as further training periodically throughout the year. Like other companies, Borderlink will sponsor visas, assist with finding housing, and even promises to have staff available 24 hours to help in the event of a medical emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the positions on offer, as well as the corporate philosophy, take a look at the website below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Altia Central&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altia Central was founded in 2001, and operates under a simple slogan: “Today’s Impression – Tomorrow’s Dream.” The company offers positions in 10 prefectures in central and southern Japan, including Aichi, Shizuoka, Gifu, Hiroshima, Osaka, Mie, Nagano, Okayama, Shiga and Fukui Prefectures, with the head office located in Nagoya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salary at Altia Central is competitive, running between ¥240,000 and ¥255,000 per month, with the extremely rare benefit (when it comes to private companies) of having fully paid summer and winter breaks. Altia also offers incentives like bonuses for renewing your contract for another year, and award money for passing certain levels of the Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT). Like other companies, it offers about a week of initial training during orientation, and follow-up training throughout the school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information, as well as current openings, visit the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. JET Programme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The JET Programme, or Japan Exchange and Teaching Programme, is a globally known, government-sponsored program that receives support from many different governmental agencies. It was created in 1987 with the goal of “increasing mutual understanding between the people of Japan and the people of other nations,” and has gone from having only four participating countries at its genesis to over 40 countries from all around the world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When compared to private companies, the JET Programme is unique for several reasons. First, the application process is quite rigorous, and if you don’t follow the programme guidelines to the T, your application won’t be considered. Another distinction worth noting is that while you’ll generally have some influence on what area of Japan you’re placed in with private companies, with JET, you are assigned a placement location, and that’s that. If you refuse that placement, you aren’t offered another, and you will no longer be considered eligible for the program in subsequent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another significant difference is the types of positions available. As well as ALTs positions, the JET program also offers CIR (Coordinator for International Relations) positions that involve working with governmental offices, and demand a high level of Japanese language ability, as well as the limited, recently-added SEA (Sports Exchange Advisor) position, which involves professional coaching of sports teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there are the perks, of which the JET program has plenty. Because of the iron-clad nature of the contract, JET provides fully paid flights to and from Japan when your contract begins and ends. Depending on the location of your placement, the programme offers spacious subsidized housing, as well as a vehicle for transportation. Salary is structured so that the longer you stay on contract, the higher you’re paid, and it starts at ¥3,360,000 for the first contract year, up to ¥3,960,000 for the fifth (and final) contract year. While you technically have to work during holidays, you’ll have over 20 vacation days to use at your discretion, as well as a separate pool of sick days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another benefit is the sense of community fostered in the JET community. Beyond the initial training and support, the JET programme has mandatory seminars as well as social organizations such as AJET to help people find their feet and feel connected when they arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information (so much information!) on the JET Programme, check out the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Direct Hire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final method we’ll discuss for becoming an ALT is somewhat of a holy grail: the direct hire. Essentially, what it means is that instead of working for a dispatch company or for the JET Programme and its various administrations, you work with a school directly, and have a contract with the local board of education (BOE). Benefits include a salary usually (but not always!) in line with the JET Programme, and positions tend to come with the flexible work time of dispatch companies, without office bigwigs breathing down your neck. Of course, as with other options, the specifics will depend on the school and board of education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct hire positions are elusive, however, and there are almost no general rules regarding how to obtain a position as a direct hire. It’s usually not something that you can just apply for from overseas, and more often than not it’s a matter of being in the right place at the right time. But there are a few ways to give yourself a realistic chance of making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s always a good idea to obtain prior experience as an ALT. Whether it’s through a dispatch company or as a JET, working as an ALT will give you valuable work experience that will help reassure potential BOEs that you’ve got a good head on your shoulders when it comes to getting the job done. This period also gives you a chance to make an impression on your present colleagues and administration officials, who might know about upcoming openings. Like any other job, networking is an important part of achieving your career goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also helps if you know Japanese. Direct hires don’t receive the same type of hand-holding provided by JET and most dispatch companies, so knowing Japanese is essential for interacting with your co-workers and handling anything that might come up in your day-to-day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also an added benefit if you’ve put down some roots and started a family, especially for visa reasons, although of course not a prerequisite. On top of being reliable and low maintenance, BOEs like to know that you’re potentially in it for the long haul. That said, there are some direct hire positions that last a maximum of three years, so be sure to check if this applies to you before you start buying property!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a more in-depth, tongue-in-cheek look at what it takes to lock down a direct hire position, click on the link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/2656/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 06:34:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2016/alt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2016/alt/</guid>
        
        <category>Teaching</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top Ten &#39;Hanami&#39; Spots in Japan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cherry blossoms are one of the most iconic natural beauties of Japan. Throughout the country, their brief but gorgeous blooming period is celebrated in an event called hanami, essentially a picnic among the blossoms with friends or loved ones. To help you plan the perfect hanami, we present 10 must-see spots throughout the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Kumamoto Castle (Kumamoto)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumamoto Prefecture—perhaps best known for its adorable bear mascot Kumamon—sits on the southern island of Kyushu. The castle here isn’t only architecturally impressive, as one of the most complete castle experiences in Japan, but also culturally, as it was the location of an important battle during the Satsuma Rebellion, a rebellion incited by Saigo Takamori that served as inspiration for the film The Last Samurai. While always a popular tourist destination, crowds flock in late March to see the hundreds of cherry blossoms trees in bloom. The grounds are especially impressive from the top floor of castle, which costs ¥500 to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Shinjuku Gyoen (Tokyo)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shinjuku Gyoen is a beautiful park in the heart of Tokyo, just a short walk from Shinjuku station. Although it costs only ¥200 to enter, that’s a small price to pay for the spacious lawns perfect for laying a blanket down, enjoying your favorite foods, and gazing on more than 1,000 cherry blossom trees contained within, which are at their prime in early April. While hanami season can be a temperamental, fickle thing, Shinjuku Gyoen contains early and late blooming trees, which makes it perfect for those who miss the elusive prime time viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Kema Sakuranomiya Park (Osaka)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kema Sakuranomiya Park is located in Osaka, and covers approximately 4 kilometers (2.5 miles) between Tenma Bridge and the Okawa Bridge. There are over 4,000 trees along the riverside, which typically bloom in early April. While the park is free to enter and there are plenty of spots along the river perfect for a picnic, there are also water buses that travel up and down the river, providing a perfect, effortless view of the whole park for a reasonable fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Mount Yoshino (Nara)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in Nara Prefecture, Mount Yoshino has been a popular hanami destination for centuries. The mountain is covered by 30,000 (!!!) cherry blossom trees that bloom from early to mid April. Due to the difference in elevation throughout its four main visiting areas, the blooming is staggered by a short period between the upper and lower sections. While there are plenty of places to stop and visit along the way, the view at the top must be seen to be believed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Hirosaki Castle (Aomori)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the northern tip of Japan’s main island of Honshu is Aomori Prefecture, home of Hirosaki Castle, former seat of the Tsuruga clan. While the castle’s walls and foundation are currently under construction, the castle grounds are open, and the main keep is scheduled to reopen in April 2016—just in time for the late April cherry blossom blooming, and Cherry Blossom Festival! Part of what sets the view here apart from other viewing destinations are “cherry blossom tunnels,” as well as the petal-filled moats, which you can experience firsthand in a romantic rental boat. It costs ¥500 for entry into the grounds and garden (although the boat will cost extra), and is a short bus ride from Hirosaki Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Hanamiyama Park (Fukushima)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside a small village in Fukushima Prefecture is Hanamiyama, a hillside park whose cherry blossom trees were originally planted by local farmers, and grew into the hanami hot spot it is today. Because it’s located in the northern region of Tohoku, the trees don’t bloom until mid-April. While the park is somewhat remote, that seclusion offers a lovely mountain view juxtaposed with the blossoms. And a ¥250 shuttle bus from Fukushima Station makes getting there a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Goryokaku Fort (Hokkaido)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goryokaku Fort is in Hakodate, on Japan’s northernmost island, Hokkaido. A short tram ride from Hakodate Station will bring you to the unique, star-shaped fort, which was turned into a public park in the early 1900s. Over 1,000 cherry blossom trees were planted along its moats, creating one of Hokkaido’s best hanami spots. Blooming usually starts in early May, and the Goryokaku Tower offers an incredible bird’s-eye view of the fortress that can’t be beat for only ¥840.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Odawara Castle (Kanagawa)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read this article then you know I’m a huge fan of Odawara Castle, the former seat of power of the Hojo in Kanagawa Prefecture. Between the farmer’s markets, ninja-related events and the fact that the castle keep has reopened to the public, a trip to the grounds would be worth it even without the added bonus of hundreds of gorgeous cherry blossoms, which usually bloom in late March. The park is also open for night viewings, making it a lovely spot for the perfect yozakura date night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Philosopher’s Walk (Kyoto)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Philosopher’s Walk is a 2-kilometer-long (1.24 miles) path that follows the canal in Kyoto’s Higashiyama district, lined with hundreds of cherry blossom trees. Named after Nishida Kitaro, a famous Japanese philosopher believed to walk the route daily on his way to Kyoto University, the path winds between Ginkakuji, the Silver Pavilion, and the neighborhood of Nanzenji. Blossoming is at its best in early April, and although the path is narrow, it’s closed to bicycles and vehicles. It’s the perfect place for sharing a breathtaking walk with a special someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Himeji Castle (Hyogo)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also called the White Heron Castle due to its pristine exterior, Himeji is widely considered to be one of (if not the) most beautiful places in the country, and one of the few castles not destroyed by war or natural disaster. It’s a national treasure, as well as a World Heritage Site, and is well worth the trip to Hyogo Prefecture. While it was under construction for years, it has reopened and only costs ¥1,000 (about US$8.80) to enter. Combine the historical and cultural significance with the fact that cherry blossoms bloom on the castle grounds in early April, and you’ve got a dream destination not to be missed by any hanami enthusiast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/2501/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 20:54:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2016/hanami-spots-japan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2016/hanami-spots-japan/</guid>
        
        <category>Japanese Culture</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All About Gachapon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Japan is a haven for toy-lovers of all stripes, a fact best demonstrated by gachapon. Gachapon, or gashapon, are iconic and ubiquitous Japanese capsule machines, and we’re here to give you the lowdown on these dial-based toy dispensers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are they?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gachapon are coin-operated toy dispensers usually ranging in price from ¥100 to ¥500. Unlike most Western toy vending machines, which are aimed at children, the contents you receive for your coins aren’t chintzy throwaways, but relatively high-quality, limited-edition goods related to your favorite piece of pop culture, making them popular among collectors and casual fans alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s anime, manga, video games, idols, or esoteric everyday items, gachapon cater to an eclectic range of interests for any age. Regardless of what you’re into, there’s a machine that offers exactly what you want—even if you don’t realize it until you finally set your eyes on it. There is, of course, an element of chaos in the mix, as there’s no guarantee you’ll get exactly what you want on your first spin. But that’s all part of the fun, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in the name?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably noticed that there are two names to refer to these toy dispensers. While both names are derived from Japanese onomatopoeia, with gacha or gasha referring to the sound of the machine being cranked—and pon the anticipatory clunk of the capsule coming down—the difference is more than just pronunciation. Both are commonly used, but gachapon is the generic name for the machines, while Gashapon is the officially licensed name registered by toy and video game giant Bandai Namco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sorts of things can you get?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the risk of sounding hyperbolic, literally almost anything can come out of one of these machines. While many gachapon provide the sort of goods you’d expect, like small figurines, key chains or cell phone straps, for every machine that does the ordinary, there’s another that gives you underwear or a weird towel to put on your household objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of machines that provide miniature versions of mundane everyday objects like chairs, shopping carts, condiments and street signs. And of course, there are machines that give you a chance at maximum cuteness, whether it’s in the form of your favorite sleeping animal or beloved characters adorably hanging onto your glass dear life. Because many items have a limited run, stocks change frequently, which means even machines you see regularly will have surprising new knickknacks to hoard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where can you find one?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gachapon can be found in and outside stores throughout the country. Arcades and stores related to gaming, electronics, anime or manga, as well as themed restaurants and cafés are almost always sure to have a block of machines to peruse. Then, of course, there are also gachapon mecca throughout Tokyo, especially in shopping districts like Akihabara or Shinjuku, where a fanatic can spend hours sorting through them to find their perfect machine (believe me, I’ve done it!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re the type that likes to plan ahead, there’s a (now-closed) thread on Reddit that contains sites that detail the location of various categories of machines, as well as suppliers, to help you find the machine that contains your dream capsule. If you can work with Japanese, the site below, Gasha-Doko (“Where’s Gasha?”), has location listings for Bandai Gashapon across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/2169/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 19:04:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2016/gachapon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2016/gachapon/</guid>
        
        <category>Japanese Culture</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ninja-Related Spots in and Around Tokyo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While it’s pretty hard to become a ninja yourself, it can be easy to get a taste if you visit the right place. Spots that celebrate the rich, secretive history of ninja can be found scattered throughout Japan—including these five right in the Tokyo area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Jidai Academy Dojo (Tabata, Tokyo)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to experience a taste of the rigorous training required of ninja, look no further than the Jidai Academy Dojo, located right in Tokyo. It’s a small establishment operated by members of the Musashi Clan, which boasts over 400 years of history, 250 of which they served under the Tokugawa Shogunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a premium of about ¥15,000 per person, you can participate in a two-hour “day in the life of” crash course, which includes fitting and changing into a gi (the preferred wardrobe of those practicing martial arts), several hands-on demonstrations of traditional ninja weapons, and lessons in meditation. For an up-charge (starting around ¥30,000) you can even partake in the ninja and samurai certification course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Odawara Castle (Odawara, Kanagawa)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in Odawara City, Kanagawa, Odawara Castle is the magnificent ancestral home of the Hojo, a powerful clan that controlled much of Kanagawa Prefecture after rising to power during the Kamakura Period (1185-1333). The Hojo were eventually defeated by Toyotomi Hideyoshi and his historic siege of the castle in 1590.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fuma were a clan of ninja that served the Hojo faithfully for many years. They specialized in horseback guerrilla warfare and naval espionage, and clan leaders each took the given name Kotaro. After the fall of the Hojo, however, they were reduced to acting as brigands around the Tokyo area, then known as Edo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they may be long gone, you can still enjoy Fuma ninja culture at Odawara Castle during the last weekend in August each year, when the Odawara Fuma Ninja Festival gives you a chance to wear a ninja costume and try throwing knives, blow darts, bows and arrows and even horseback riding! Information on this and other ninja-related events can be found at the Odawara-shi Tourist Association website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Edo Wonderland (Nikko, Tochigi)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A true ninja finds time to step away from Nikko’s many national treasures and UNESCO World Heritage sites to visit Edo Wonderland, a theme park in Tochigi Prefecture that offers a traditional blast from the past. Edo Wonderland is an amusement park unlike any other, offering all the ambiance and entertainment you would expect if you visited Japan in the Edo Period (1603-1868).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, of course, includes a course on the art of the ninja. The theme park offers courses that can be enjoyed by both kids and adults, teaching you how to throw shuriken (ninja throwing stars) as well as ninja movement and concealing techniques. After striking down your enemies from the shadows, be sure to visit one of the many dining venues or catch a period-appropriate performance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Bujinkan Dojo (Noda City, Chiba)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bujinkan dojo, based in Chiba Prefecture, is the home base for the International Bujinkan Dojo Association, which is dedicated to the rigorous study of nine different martial arts, including ninpo, more commonly known as ninjutsu. While previous entries on this list offer one-off experiences, the Bujinkan offers a highly regimented means of mastering the art of the ninja that’s very foreigner-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the website looks as ancient as the martial arts the organization practices, Bujinkan is the real deal. Founder Masaaki Hatsumi has dedicated his life to the proliferation of Japanese martial arts (and worked as a martial arts consultant for the movie biz!), and the classes on offer are expertly organized. Ninja hopefuls must rise through the ranks by mastering the basics before earning their belts. Check out the website for information on where to enroll (and the associated costs), as well as alternate education options if there isn’t a dojo in your area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Ninja Akasaka (Akasaka, Tokyo)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokyo is home to an incredible breadth of themed restaurants, but none of them hold a candle to Ninja Akasaka, the preferred eatery of a true shinobi. The exterior is designed to resemble a traditional ninja house, complete with dark rooms, winding staircases and mysterious corridors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you arrive inside, you’ll be greeted by a master of the shadowy arts who will show you to your seats and give you a brief overview of the menu. While the à-la-carte dishes range in price from ¥600 to ¥10,000, the restaurant also offers course menus for parties of various sizes. Most of the fare is appropriately kitschy, and between the eats and the entertainment, you’ll be sure to get your fill of all things ninja!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/2086/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 18:04:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2016/ninjas-in-tokyo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2016/ninjas-in-tokyo/</guid>
        
        <category>Japanese Culture</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Great Burrito in the Tokyo Desert</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Homegrown Japanese food culture is famous the world over for its depth of flavor, affordability, and relative healthiness (especially when compared to equivalent Western fare). But there are times you want to take a culinary journey to a different part of the world without leaving Tokyo. Maybe south of the border—the U.S./Mexico border, that is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the 2015 return of U.S. Tex-Mex fast food franchise Taco Bell to the heart of Tokyo, it’s clear that the idea of Mexican food is gaining popularity in Japan. But that doesn’t change the fact that the execution is a bit lacking, as it’s still quite difficult to find establishments that deliver authentic flavor and let you leave with both your stomach and your wallet full. It’s like wandering through a barren desert hoping to stumble across a lush cactus—which is exactly what I did on my way home from work one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short train ride into Kawasaki on JR’s Nambu line to Musashi-Shinjo Station, and a 10-minute walk beyond that, lies A Cactus in the Desert, which opened in 2007. Affectionately called Cactus Burrito, or simply Cactus, by those that frequent the joint, this low-key hole in the wall is instantly recognizable by its affectionately fostered Southern California skater style and the mouth-watering aromas that fill the air as soon as you get close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you step inside, do yourself a favor and grab a seat at the bar. From there, you can watch chef, co-owner and all around rock star Naoko meticulously prepare the most authentic burrito I’ve had on Japanese soil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the small size of the restaurant belies the extensiveness of the menu (Fresh Guacamole? Check. Face-sized plate of carne-asada nachos? Check! Tequila? Si!), the burritos are the true stars of the show. Naoko makes each one to order, and while the process is time consuming, it’s definitely worth the wait. Whether it’s delivered on a hot plate, smothered in enchilada sauce and cheese, or served up in foil like Chipotle’s better-looking cousin, you’re guaranteed to scratch your culinary itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the food—which it does so right—Cactus Burrito (and all of the super-friendly women who work there) has cultivated a certain culture, creating a restaurant that offers customers an environment that’s both edgy and inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They offer happy hour most nights (with discounts on drinks and menu items), skateboard and burrito day usually once a month (which is basically exactly what it sounds like), and a delicious-sounding brunch service on Saturdays that I’ve yet to have the pleasure of trying. Beyond that, they sell a variety of small-press publications that they distribute from Microcosm Publishing, as well as other merchandise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all this hasn’t convinced you, or you’d like a little more information, feel free to check out their website here or their Facebook page (which is constantly updated with the restaurant operating hours, upcoming events, and more). Do yourself a favor, and try it first-hand. Your stomach will thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Kanagawa, Kawasaki-shi, Takatsu-ku, 1045 Chitose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://allabout-japan.com/en/article/1254/&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 17:04:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll-uno//2015/burrito-tokyo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll-uno//2015/burrito-tokyo/</guid>
        
        <category>Food</category>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
